alshaya.com 2013-12-19

# Alshaya - Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

**Overview**

Alshaya.com is strongly committed to respecting the privacy of all persons using our website, <http://www.alshaya.com/> ("the **Web Site** ") and the protection of any personally identifiable information which we may collect and/ or use as part of our data collection process and/ or which you may choose to share with us. Such personal information will be collected and/ or used in accordance with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, which is part of and incorporated into the [Terms of Use](http://www.alshaya.com/terms/terms/terms-of-use/) of the Web Site.

**Your Express Consent to Collection and Use of Information**

We reserve the right to collect such personally identifiable information as, name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, etc., as well as demographic and profile data such as IP address, internet domain or browser, referrer or user agent information or other relevant information that we use as part of our data collection process, such as the use of cookies or certain other information you may provide to us, etc. (" **Personal Information** ") as set forth in this Privacy Policy. We hold all such Personal Information on secure servers and treat it as fully confidential.

**BY CHOOSING TO ACCESS THE WEB SITE, YOU ARE INDICATING YOUR EXPRESS CONSENT AND AGREEMENT TO THE COLLECTION, TRANSFER, PROCESSING, USE AND STORAGE IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY OF ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION WHICH MAY BE OBTAINED FROM YOU AS A RESULT OF YOUR ACCESSING OR USE OF THE WEB SITE, ANY OF WHICH MAY OCCUR EITHER OR BOTH INSIDE AND OUTSIDE OF THE STATE OF KUWAIT IN JURISDICTIONS WHERE LEGAL PROTECTION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT.** If you do not agree with any of the terms and conditions set forth in the Privacy Policy, or have any questions, please do not access the Web Site or contact us directly at [webmaster@alshaya.com](mailto:webmaster@alshaya.com), and we will be pleased to assist you. By accessing or using the Web Site, you grant Alshaya a non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free perpetual license to use your Personal Information for the purposes set forth herein.

**Collection / Use of Data**

When you register on our website, we collect certain personal information from you, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address etc (“Personal Data”). We hold all such Personal Data on secure servers and treat it as fully confidential.

We will not sell your Personal Data to third parties. We do, however, share customer information with the following third parties:

• our group companies;

• our franchisors;

• third party databases to which Alshaya and/or one of our brands subscribes; government bodies or other authorities if necessary to comply with regulations or law or to assist with law enforcement, or to protect our property and other rights;

• agencies who help us collate statistics about site traffic, sales, demographics and other commercial information to enable us to tailor the services we provide to you and other customers.

By submitting your Personal Data through our website, you agree to the transfer, storage and processing of such data outside of the European Economic Area.

We will retain your Personal Data for as long as it is legally required, and to support the business purposes for which it was obtained - we will then dispose of it promptly and securely.

**Cookies**

As part of our normal data collection process, the Web Site may deposit "cookies" in your device in order to identify you and/ or as a means of tracking the validity of sessions as well as enhancing your browsing experience. Cookies are small pieces of data that a website automatically sends to your computer, tablet or mobile phone while you are viewing the website.

We use two types of cookies on our website:

• “Session” cookies, which are used to allow you to:

• carry information from one page of our website to another without having to re-enter information; and

• access stored information when you are logged in to your online account.

• “Persistent” cookies, which allow us to offer you tailored content on our website by helping us to remember:

• any personal information that you have provided on previous visits to our website;

• the number of visits that you have made to our website; and

• your preferences

Third parties are not able to identify customers using cookies.

We also reserve the right to use an outside advertising company to display ads on the Web Site. These ads may also contain cookies. While we may use cookies in other parts of our Web site, cookies received with banner ads or from other third-party sources may be collected by any such third-party companies, and we do not have direct access to or control over such processes. No cookies used by Alshaya are stored permanently on your device. All cookies are automatically removed from your device either when you close your browser or your session times out.

By using our website, you agree to the placing of cookies on your device. However, if you do not want to receive a cookie from our website, you may set your browser to refuse cookies or to notify you when you receive a cookie (to find out how to do this, please consult your browser’s help section). If cookies aren’t enabled on your device, it may limit your enjoyment of the Web Site.

To enable cookies:

If you're not sure of the type and version of web browser you use to access the Internet:

**For PCs:** click on 'Help' at the top of your browser window and select the 'About' option

**For Macs:** with the browser window open, click on the Apple menu and select the 'About' option

If you'd like to learn more about cookies in general and how to manage them, visit [aboutcookies.org](http://aboutcookies.org/) (opens in a new window).

If you'd like to opt out of cookies, please go to the [Network Advertising Initiative website](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) (opens in a new window).

Please note that we're not responsible for the content of external websites.

**Protection of Personal Information Against Third-Party Access or Use**

We store all Personal Information on a secure server and we seek to use procedures designed to protect Personal Information from accidental or unauthorised access, destruction, use, modification or disclosure. We will seek to ensure that your Personal Information is kept confidential and secure in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and that the appropriate technical and organisational measures to prevent unlawful or accidental destruction, accidental loss, unauthorised disclosure or access or other unlawful forms of processing are implemented. Although we will strive to take commercially reasonable security precautions regarding all Personal Information, visitors or users to the Web Site acknowledge and agree that Alshaya does not control the transfer of information or data via the Web Site or over any other electronic facilities or media. We will retain your Personal Information for as long as it is legally required, and to support the business purposes for which it was obtained – we will then dispose of it promptly and securely.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

Since we are constantly making changes and upgrades to our systems and services in order to better serve you, we anticipate updating this Privacy Policy from time-to-time. Therefore, we reserve the right to revise or alter the content of this Privacy Policy in any manner and at any time, without notice. Your subsequent and/ or continued use of any portion of the Web Site following a posting of changes to the Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such changes.

**Third Party Web Sites**

You may be able to access certain third-party websites through links on the Web Site. We are not, however, responsible for any other websites, their respective privacy policies or other content nor how they treat information about their visitors or users. We strongly advise you to check their privacy policies to find out how they are treating your Personal Information.

**No Warranty**

YOU UNDERSTAND THAT ALSHAYA DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY WARRANTY, GUARANTEE OR REPRESENTATION OF ANY KIND CONCERNING OUR ABILITY TO CONTROL, COLLECT, CORRECT, ACCESS, PROCESS, USE, STORE, PROTECT OR TRANSFER ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION OR CONCERNING THE EXISTENCE OR EFFECTIVENESS OF ANY SECURITY MEASURES UNDERTAKEN BY US. YOU AGREE THAT ALSHAYA WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIMS, LOSSES, OR DAMAGES OF ANY KIND WHATSOEVER WHICH MAY RESULT FROM THE ACCESS, DISCLOSURE, USE OR MODIFICATION BY ANY PARTY NOT AUTHORISED OR AUTHORISED BY US, OR THE INTRODUCTION OF VIRUSES, WORMS, OR OTHER HARMFUL ELEMENTS INTO THE SYSTEM AND THEIR POSSIBLE EFFECTS ON PERSONAL INFORMATION CONTAINED ON THE WEB SITE. By accessing or using the Web Site, you acknowledge that you understand and agree to assume these risks.

**Limitation of Liability**

**IN NO EVENT WILL ALSHAYA, ITS AFFILIATES, PARTNERS, AND THEIR RESPECTIVE EMPLOYEES, OFFICERS, DIRECTORS OR INSURERS BE LIABLE TO YOU OR TO ANY OTHER PERSON FOR ANY COSTS, DAMAGES (INCLUDING ANY SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES), OR LIABILITY OF ANY NATURE, ARISING OR RESULTING FROM THE COLLECTION, USE, TRANSFER, PROCESSING OR STORAGE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION OBTAINED BY US AND RESULTING FROM YOUR ACCESS TO AND USE OF THE WEB SITE.**

**Governing Law; Jurisdiction**

****This Privacy Policy will be governed by the laws of the State of Kuwait. The exclusive jurisdiction for any claim, action or dispute with Alshaya or relating in any way to your use of the Web Site will be in the appropriate courts of the State of Kuwait and the venue for the adjudication or disposition of any such claim, action or dispute will be in the State of Kuwait.
